<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kesugi Ridge Traverse</title>
    <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kesugi Ridge Traverse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 23:15:22 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Race update June 12, 2020</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/notice/notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 23:15:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/notice/notice/</guid>
      <description>We do not yet have clearance to open lottery registration as planned on June 15, but are working with Alaska State Parks on a COVID-19 mitigation race plan and are hopeful to open registration soon.
The race, if it happens, will be conducted differently this year. Here is what has been proposed to Alaska State Parks:
 Kesugi Ridge Traverse 30-mile ONLY. (To simplify race logistics and alleviate parking challenges at the tiny Ermine Hill Trailhead, there will NOT be a 15-mile Half Traverse in 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race Info</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/race-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/race-info/</guid>
      <description>What: 8th Kesugi Ridge Traverse &amp;amp; 4th Kesugi Ridge Half Traverse
When: August 29th, 2020, 9 a.m.
Start Location: Denali State Park, Little Coal Creek Trailhead (Mile 164 Parks Highway)
Entry Fee: $65 on-line (registration fee is included).
Lottery Registration: Begins at 9 a.m. Monday, June 15 at UltraSignup and ends at 11:59 p.m. on Friday, June 19. Limited to 100 total entrants (50 for each race). See registration requirements below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Description</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:43:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/course/</guid>
      <description>The point-to-point Kesugi Full Traverse starts at Little Coal Creek Trailhead and finishes at Byers Lake Campground. It is approximately 30 miles.
The Kesugi Ridge Half Traverse starts at Little Coal Creek Trailhead and finishes just beyond the Ermine Hill Trail Junction. It is approximately 14.2 miles. (Participants will then travel 3.5 miles at their own leisure to the Parks Highway via the Ermine Hill Trail).
Detailed descriptions can be found in the hiking guides 55 Ways to the Wilderness (5th edition) by Helen Nienhueser &amp;amp; John Wolfe Jr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map &amp; Profile</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:43:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/map/</guid>
      <description>Download KML File for the course</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 23:15:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/requirements/</guid>
      <description>Qualifying Trail Participants for the Full Traverse must have completed one of the following since 2017 at a pace within the Kesugi race cutoff pace: Kesugi Ridge Trail, Crow Pass Crossing, Resurrection Pass Trail, Lost Lake Trail, Matanuska Peak Challenge, Granite Tors, Angel Creek 50, Johnson Pass, Juneau’s Nifty 50 or a comparable race.
Participants for the Half Traverse must have completed 15 miles of one of the above trails since 2017, or 15 miles of a comparable race, at a pace within the Kesugi race cutoff pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race Details</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 23:15:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/rules/</guid>
      <description>Bibs can be picked up at Byers Lake Headquarters from 5-9 p.m. the night before the race, or at Little Coal Creek Trailhead on race morning from 7-8:45 a.m. We will NOT meet on race day at Byers Lake. Participants are responsible for their transportation to the Little Coal Creek start, either by official shuttle from Byers Lake (subject to space availability) or personal vehicle (please carpool). All participants must sign in at Little Coal Creek by 8:45 a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/faq/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:43:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/faq/faq/</guid>
      <description>What does K’esugi mean?  It means the Ancient One in Dena’ina. Traditionally the area was used as caribou hunting grounds.
 Who are the two Dave Johnstons?  Dave Johnston the Elder (of Minus 148 Degrees fame) helped build the original trail in the mid-1970s, along with Pete Robinson, George Menard and the Youth Conservation Corps. It took 3-4 years to put in the basic trail. Brian Okonek had the idea to use Kesugi’s lateral moraine instead of some of the surrounding high country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/contact/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 23:36:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/contact/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/registration/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 22:49:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/registration/registration/</guid>
      <description>Registration opens April 1, 2017 at UltraSignup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteers</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/volunteers/volunteers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/volunteers/volunteers/</guid>
      <description>The event needs a host of volunteers, including sweepers, shuttle drivers, burger flippers and result-takers. Anyone interested in volunteering should contact the race director. Key volunteers will receive free entry for 2020, free camping, race swag and eternal gratitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/results/results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 22:49:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/results/results/</guid>
      <description>2019 Results:
30 miler with splits
Kesugi Half Results
Results for 2013-18 can be found on UltraSignup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsors</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/sponsors/sponsors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/sponsors/sponsors/</guid>
      <description>Alaska Mountain Runners  Check out the race calendar at www.alaskamountainrunners.com
    The Alaska Sports Hall of Fame and Healthy Futures program  Helping keep Alaskans healthy
    USATF  The Kesugi Ridge Traverse &amp;amp; Half Traverse is a USATF sanctioned event.
    49th State Brewing Co.  Brewpubs in downtown Anchorage and Denali Park.
    United Physical Therapy  Clinics in downtown Anchorage, Midtown Anchorage and South Anchorage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>